



SKILLS & INTERESTS

- LANGUAGES: Ruby, Javascript, HTML5, CSS3, Swift, R, VBA
- FRAMEWORKS: Rails, Sinatra, learning Node
- DATABASES: PostgreSQL, SQLite3,
- TESTING: RSpec, Jasmine, Capybara
- METHODOLOGIES: OOD, TDD, BDD, MVC, RESTful
- Fast learner and highly motivated with great analytical, problem-solving and communication skills.
- Interests include practicing yoga, snowboarding, discovering/listening to good music, hiking, playing the guitar & ukulele

PROJECTS

BOOKIT BUCKET | source

Bookit Bucket list sharing app written in Ruby on Rails. It allows users to create bucket lists (private, public, or with groups of friends) and view/follow/rate/attend with other friends in order to spread great ideas/places/things to do.

I'M IN | source

"I'm In" is a 7-day project written in Swift, that is an easy-to-use event planning mobile app. It allows users to seamlessly join in on events and chat with friends, I was in charge of the backend (RoRails), created the Rails web app, implemented the chat feature (Firebase), worked on connecting the database to the mobile app and wrote many of the features in Swift.

TRANSLATEYO! | source

TranslateYo! is a user-friendly translator written in Ruby on Rails using the Bing Translator API, that lets users correct translations posted by other users. I was in charge of the Front-end, using Javascript, three, is and Bootstrap.

OOJS RACER | source

OOJS Racer is a simple racing game including avatars and modals written in OOJS with a Sinatra backend.

WORK EXPERIENCE

GENERAL STAR & GENESIS, subsidiaries of Gen Re, Stamford, CT

February 2011 – May 2014

Actuary

- Prepared annual rate study presentations for the Contract Property & Casualty and Brokerage Property dept.
- Analyzed trended loss experience tables, major trends, claim history, and effective rate changes to provide expected loss ratios and indicated rate changes for each line of business.
- Annually prepared Benchmark Reported Loss Ratio Reports to determine measurements against client reported loss ratios; this also includes the development of expense ratios and permissible loss ratios.
- Reverse-engineered Risk Management Solutions catastrophe models by designing GLMs with R
- Tested system replacement tools and performed quality assurance assessments on finalized products.
- Active member of the Cultural Enhancement Committee, Welcoming Team and Tech Training Committee.

SOLIYA, Inc., New York, NY

October 2010 - December 2010

Finance and Operations Intern

- Hands-on experience in the administration of a growing international non-profit organization.
- Assist with operations, finance and office management projects such as maintaining vendor files and accounts.
- Learn about and helped with the upkeep of accounts payable systems.
- Updated computer programs for coding bills, filing past invoices and general bookkeeping.

EDUCATION

DEV BOOTCAMP. New York, NY Ruby on Rails Full-Stack Developer June 2014 – August 2014

UNIVERSITY OF MICHIGAN, Ann Arbor, MI Bachelor of Science, Financial Mathematics September 2006 – May 2014

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

ALPHA KAPPA DELTA PHI, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor

September 2006 - May 2010

Vice President of Internal Affairs, New Member Educator, Social Chair

- Official contact and representative for the UMich Chapter for all sorority sisters nationwide
- Oversaw planning of all events and was Head Coordinator of the Midwest Sisterhood Conference